Linda LaMacchia collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 1: Fieldwork in Northwest India
  - Subseries 2: Additional fieldwork
    - Graphic materials
      - India trip, April-July 2015, 40 color negatives (35 mm); 39 color prints (4x6); AFC 2017/049: PH046 (Box 13, Box 15)
      - India trip, April-July 2015, afc2017049_dc53; 72 still images (jpg)
    - Video footage
      - [Puppy's ashes and New Year's dance], 2008-2009, afc2017049_dc45; 7 moving image files (vob, ifo)
      - [Puppy's ashes and New Year's dance], November 1, 2012, afc2017049_dc23; 1 moving image file (mov)
      - [Production files for Puppy's ashes and New Year's dance video], undated, afc2017049_dc60; 33 still image files (jpg), 16 moving images files (mov, mp4); 2 audio files (aiff)
      - India videos, December 2012-February 2013, afc2017049_dc17; 18 moving image files (mp4)
      - [ Buddhist Women Masters of Kinnaur: Gurus, Disciples, Modern Curriculum, and Traditional Songs ], May 10, 2013, afc2017049_dc13; 1 moving image file (mov)
      - India footage, August 15-October 15, 2013, afc2017049_dc24; 20 moving image files (mp4)
      - India, December 9, 2013, afc2017049_dc61; 3 moving image files (mp4)
      - [ Buddhist Women Masters of Kinnaur: Gurus, Disciples, Modern Curriculum, and Traditional Songs ] DVD NTSC original, 2013, afc2017049_dc14; 7 moving image files (vob, ifo)
      - India, July-September 2014, afc2017049_dc03; 13 moving image files (mp4), 1 still image file (jpg)
      - India trip, April-July 2015, afc2017049_dc57; 25 moving image files (mp4)
      - Manuscript material accompanying digital media: afc2017049_dc57 through afc2017049_dc62, 1 folder (Box-folder 16/11)
    - Administrative files
      - [Buddhist religious text given to Linda LaMacchia by Lama Nyima, village head lama, Lippa], December 26, 2012, 1 folder (Box-folder 5/18)
      - [Correspondence about Tibet; video editing], 2013, 1 folder (Box-folder 5/19)
      - Phone messages, February 7-8, 2016, AFC 2017/049: SR033; 1 sound cassette
      - Manuscript materials that accompanied sound recordings, AFC 2017/049: SR004-SR055, 1992-2015, 1 folder (Box-folder 5/20)
      - Manuscript materials that accompanied sound recordings, AFC 2017/049: SR056-SR143, 1992-2015, 1 folder (Box-folder 5/21)
      - [Recording inventory], 2013-2014, 1 folder (Box-folder 5/22)
      - [Recording logs], 2003-2008, 1 folder (Box-folder 5/23)
- Series 2: Academic files
  Professional correspondence, book and article drafts, conference presentations, grant proposals, teaching files, and other materials related to LaMacchia's academic career.
  - Subseries 1: Publications and drafts
    - [ A Kinnauri Nun's Song article drafts], 1992, 1 folder (Box-folder 5/24)
    - [ Appendix: Case Studies draft], May 20, 1999, 1 folder (Box-folder 5/25)
    - [ Basic Buddhism in Songs: Contemporary Nuns' Oral Traditions in Kinnaur article drafts], 2014-2015, 1 folder (Box-folder 5/26)
    - [ Buddhist Women Masters of Kinnaur: Why Nuns Don't Sing About Nuns article drafts], 2012-2016, 1 folder (Box-folder 5/27)
    - Chapter 3: Song Exegesis, Lobon, Lotsa, January 1999, 1 folder (Box-folder 5/28)
    - Current paper (feminism) related articles and emails, September 2016, 1 folder (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Death of Negi Lama in 1977 in The Tibet Journal, 2012, 1 folder (Box-folder 6/2)
    - [Dissertation bibliography drafts], 1994-1995, afc2017049_dc05; 3 text files (wpd)
    - [Dissertation Chapter 1 and Chapter 4 drafts], October 1-November 23, 1999, afc2017049_dc06; 3 text files (doc)
    - [Dissertation drafts], July-September 1998, afc2017049_dc09; 3 text files (doc, wpd)
    - [Dissertation outline, chapter drafts, appendix drafts], February 16, 1999, afc2017049_dc04; 7 text files (doc)
    - Feminism and the Everyday Lives of Buddhist Nuns and Monks of Kinnaur, 2016, 1 folder (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Hirmal and Lossary, 2000-2001, 1 folder (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Kinnauri Nun's Song, 1992, 1 folder (Box-folder 6/5)
    - Photos for MSS Songs and Lives of the Jomo (Nuns) of Kinnaur, Northwest India, December 22, 2007, AFC 2017/049: PH025; 2 color negatives (35 mm) (Box 13)
    - Photos for Songs and Lives of the Jomo (Nuns) of Kinnaur, Northwest India, December 22, 2007, AFC 2017/049: PH039; 2 black-and-white prints (4x6) (Box 14)
    - Plates, undated, 1 folder (Box-folder 6/6)
    - [Project proposals], October-November 2009, afc2017049_dc12; 2 text files (doc)
    - Songs and Lives of the Jomo (Nuns) of Kinnaur, Northwest India, 2008, 1 folder (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Two Song Genres and Changing Identities of Mayahana Buddhist Nuns of Kinnaur (H.P.) India in The Tibet Journal, 2007, 1 folder (Box-folder 6/8)
    - [University of Wisconsin paper drafts], 1988-1993, afc2017049_dc12; 2 text files (doc)
    - Women's Religious Expression in Tibetan Buddhism: Religious Songs and Lives of the Jomo (Nuns) of Kinnaur, Northwest India [dissertation], 2001, 1 folder (Box-folder 6/9)
  - Subseries 2: Conferences
    - [ Buddhist Nuns in India Through Their Life Stories and Songs: The Example of Kinnaur conference presentation], February 28, 2014, 1 folder (Box-folder 6/11)
    - [ Buddhist Nuns in India Through Their Life Stories and Songs: The Example of Kinnaur conference presentation], February 28, 2014, 1 folder (Box-folder 6/12)
    - [ Buddhist Women Masters of Kinnaur: Why Don't Nuns Sing About Nuns? conference presentation], November 22, 2013, 1 folder (Box-folder 6/13)
    - [Conference abstracts], 2013, 1 folder (Box-folder 6/14)
    - Losar in Kinnaur: songs & interviews & journal transcripts, transcripts (Ramesh, HPN), [materials for the Conference on the Study of Religions of India], 2009-2010, 1 folder (Box-folder 6/10)
    - [Mid-Atlantic Academy of Religion conference], 2011-2012, 1 folder (Box-folder 6/15)
    - [ Relationships and Interdependence in Renunciants' Lives: Community Connections, Family Ties, and Cooperation between Jomos and Lamas in Kinnaur conference presentation], 2014, 1 folder (Box-folder 6/16)
    - [ Religious Multiculturalism as Opportunity for Buddhist Nuns: The Case of Kinnaur and the Bon Ordination of Bhikshuni Chattan Mani presentation at American Academy of Religion conference], March 17, 2012, 1 folder (Box-folder 6/17)
  - Subseries 3: Other personal and professional pursuits
    - [ Buddhist Nuns in India Through Their Life Stories and Songs: The Example of Kinnaur webinar for the Social Science Club at University of Maryland's University College], February 28, 2014, afc2017049_dc51; 9 moving image files (vob, ifo)
    - [ Buddhist Nuns in India Through Their Life Stories and Songs: The Example of Kinnaur webinar for the Social Science Club at University of Maryland University College], February 28, 2014, afc2017049_dc57; 5 moving image files (mov, prproj)
    - [Fulbright project statement], 1994, afc2017049_dc05; 1 text file (wpd)
    - [Fulbright project statement], August 1, 2012, 1 folder (Box-folder 6/18)
    - [Guest lecturer for ANTH398S, University of Maryland's University College], 2009, 1 folder (Box-folder 6/19)
    - Ka Shin Zendo Genzo-Ji 40th Anniversary: A Collection of Images from Ka Shin Zendo Genzo-Ji, 2009, afc2017049_dc48; 1 moving image file (wmv)
    - [Linda LaMacchia curriculum vitae], 1994, afc2017049_dc05; 1 text file (wpd)
    - [Linda LaMacchia curriculum vitae], November 2009, afc2017049_dc12; 2 text files (doc)
    - [Linda LaMacchia curriculum vitae], undated, 1 folder (Box-folder 6/20)
    - [Linda LaMacchia obituary], 2017, 1 folder (Box-folder 6/21)
    - [MA and PhD coursework], 1994, afc2017049_dc05; 4 text files (wpd)
    - [Professional references], 1999, 1 folder (Box-folder 6/22)
    - [University of Wisconsin Course Guides edited by Linda LaMacchia], 1994, afc2017049_dc05; 9 text files (edt, wpd, let)
    - [Writing assignments], 1998, afc2017049_dc09; 1 text file (wpd)
- Series 3: Personal travel to India
  Photographs from LaMacchia's personal travels to multiple regions of India prior to her fieldwork in the Kinnaur district.
  - [Trip to India], 1985-1986, AFC 2017/049: PH001; 120 color slides (35 mm) (Box 8)
  - School excursion to Panch, Christmas (pilgrimage circle around Benares), leper ashrams, boat ride part of tour in Bangalore, Mom and Dad on Ganges in Benares, 1989-1990, AFC 2017/049: PH011; 34 color slides (35 mm) (Box 10)
  - Hindi class excursion in Uttar Pradesh, near dam, Christmas vacation 1989 in Madras (hotel), Bangalore, Mysore, and Sera Je, David Patt, Michael, and Geshe, 1989-1990, AFC 2017/049: PH012; 25 color slides (35 mm) (Box 10)
  - [Trip to India], circa 1989-circa 1990, AFC 2017/049: PH047; 103 black-and-white prints (3.5x5); 4 color prints (3.5x5) (Box 15)
  - Varanasi, Lathuji at home, Rupali on Ganges, Kathak poses, May 1990, AFC 2017:049: PH009; 20 color slides (35 mm) (Box 10)
  - Varanasi at parting, Panditji's songs with van, Harriet's adopted daughter and son, neighbors' children, Mairi, May 1990, AFC 2017/049: PH013; 20 color slides (35 mm) (Box 10)
  - Dharamsala, Jogivara Road, Nagyu Gongre (Jampa and Pema), Delhi, Najur Ka Tila (Pema and Parang and Sarah), Wedding with Chinchilla, Syam, Nyima, puppy, new house (on Tippa Road), Ani Tencho at Ani Gorpe gate (performing after school), September 1990, AFC 2017/049: PH015; 20 color slides (35 mm) (Box 10)
  - Larki, view from Omala's house, McLeod Ganj (Dramas School Road), Des Raj, Keylong, Kaguju Gompa, Kadang village, Manali, October 1990, 25 color slides (35 mm); 7 color slides (35 mm); AFC 2017/049: PH016 (Box 10, Box 11)
  - Ganga, ghats, 1990, AFC 2017/049: PH010; 20 color slides (35 mm) (Box 10)
  - Darjeeling, Mussouri, Tso Pema, Dharamsala, 1990, AFC 2017/049: PH014; 30 color slides (35 mm) (Box 10)
  - [Trip to India], undated, AFC 2017/049: PH049; 1 color print (3.5x4); 1 black-and-white print (7x2) (Box 15)
- Electronic media, Optical discs that originally housed digital files from afc2017049_dc01 to afc2017049_dc09, afc2017049_dc12 to afc2017049_dc14, afc2017049_dc16 to afc2017049_dc17, afc2017049_dc23 to afc2017049_dc34, afc2017049_dc36, afc2017049_dc38 to afc2017049_dc41, afc2017049_dc45, afc2017049_dc48 to afc2017049_dc56, and afc2017049_dc62 to afc2017049_dc67.; 40 optical discs; 7 floppy disks (3.5 in.) (Box 17)
Related Publications
LaMacchia, Linda. Buddhist Women Masters of Kinnaur: Why Don't Nuns Sing About Nuns? International Journal of Dharma Studies 4, no. 5 (2016).
LaMacchia, Linda. Death of Negi Lama in Lahul (H.P.), India, in 1977. The Tibet Journal 37, no. 1 (Spring 2012): 3-16.
LaMacchia, Linda. Songs and Lives of the Jomo (Nuns) of Kinnaur, Northwest India: Women's Religious Expression in Tibetan Buddhism. Delhi, India: Sri Satguru Publications, 2008.
LaMacchia, Linda. Two Song Genres and Changing Identities of Mayahana Buddhist Nuns of Kinnaur (H.P.) India. The Tibet Journal 32, no. 4 (Winter 2007): 61-69.
LaMacchia, Linda. Women's Religious Expression in Tibetan Buddhism: Songs and Lives of the Jomo (Nuns) of Kinnaur, Northwest India. PhD dissertation, University of Wisconsin, Madison, 2001.
Appendix A: List of jomos, lamas, and scholars interviewed during dissertation fieldwork
List of jomos, lamas, and scholars that LaMacchia interviewed during her dissertation fieldwork in the Kinnaur district. Information is drawn from the appendix of LaMacchia's book Songs and Lives of the Jomo (Nuns) of Kinnaur, Northwest India and from title headings and manuscript materials in the collection.
Jomos
Ani Dolma Chango Manali
Anonymous Charang Dehra Dun
Anonymous Moorang Dehra Dun
Bogti Tokto
Chos Nyid Zangmo Charang Manali Chos Nyid Sangmo
Chosem Dolma Bure
Choskyi Wangmo Chango Tilokpur
Chozing Palmo Lippa
Durum Dolma Nesang Tabo
Gedun Zangmo Tokto
Hirmal Lippa
Jamuna Bagh Bure
Jangsem Sapni
Jigme Choden Lippa Dehra Dun
Karma Dechen Chango Sherab Ling
Karma Rinchen Zangmo Chango Tilokpur
Karma Thinley Chango Tilokpur
Kunzig Palmo Nesang Tabo
Lobsang Choeden Bhaba Tso Pema or Rewalsar
Lobsang Dolma Lippa
Lobsang Palzin Bure Dharmsala
Lotsa Rinpoche
Naryan Dolma Nesang Tabo
Samten Dolma Charang Manali
Samten Wangmo Lippa Dehra Dun
Sanjeevmani Ribba
Sherab Wangmo Chango Tilokpur
Sonam Dekyi Ribba Dharmsala
Sonam Tsomo Nesang Tabo
Sonam Wangmo Chango Tilokpur
Sushmila Spello
Tenzin Choeden Charang Manali Tenzim Choeden
Tenzin Dedin Kanum Dharmsala Tenzin Deden
Tenzin Dolma Chango Manali
Tenzin Kinzum Powari Garo
Tenzin Nangsal Kanum Dharmsala
Tenzin Palyon Panwi Dharmsala
Tenzin Tsomo Kanum Dharmsala Tenzen Tsomo
Tenzin Zangmo Kanum Dharmsala
Thinley Dolma Tokto
Thupten Choeden Bure Dharmsala
Thupten Chozing Kanum Dharmsala Thupten Choezing
Tsering Chango Tilokpur
Tsering Choekyi/Jimbu Devi Charang Manali
Tsering Lhamo Ribba
Tsultrim Angmo Chango Manali
Tsultrim Tsomo Charang Manali
Upal Devi Kanum Tabo
Yangchen Dolma Nichar Sarnath Yongchen Dolma
Yangchen Dolma Panwi
Lamas and Scholars
Bhagwan Singh Jangi Panwi
Choegon Rinpoche Khadura Tashi Jong Choegen Rinpoche
Gopal Chand Negi Spello Simla
Hirapal Ganga Negi Kanum Delhi Hirapel Ganga Negi
Jita Sen Negi Giabong Sarnath
Lama Topgyal Chango Sarnath
Lochen Tulku Shelkar Delhi
Negi Tulku Denmark Dehra Dun
Ramesh Chandra Negi Jangi Mathas
Sempa Dorje Dubling Sarnath Sempa Dorjo
Somang Tulku Tashi Jong
Sonam Deva Samarka
Tenzin Choezang Lippa
Vidyasagar Negi Asarang Simla Vidhya Sagar Negi
Wangchu Dorje Jangi Sarnath Wangju Dorje or Wangchuk Dorje
Yulgyal Tulku Jangi and Gautam Nagar
Tibetans
Ga Rinpoche Dehra Dun Gaa Rinpoche
Konchok Gyaltsen Dehra Dun Khenchen Konchok Gyaltsen
Lobsang Samten "Tiny" McLeod Ganj
Ontrul Rinpoche Chicago Ontul Rinpoche
Sherab Zangmo Manali
Thupten Woser Manali, Sarnath Khenpo Thupten Woser or Khenpo Thupten
Appendix B: List of jomos, lamas, and scholars interviewed during additional fieldwork
List of jomos, lamas, and scholars that LaMacchia interviewed during her additional fieldwork in the Kinnaur district. Information is drawn from the appendix of LaMacchia's book Songs and Lives of the Jomo (Nuns) of Kinnaur, Northwest India and from title headings and manuscript materials in the collection.
Jomos
Lobsang Dolma Lippa
Sonam Choeden
Sonam Dekyi Ribba
Tenzin Palyon Panwi Shanti
Tenzin Zangmo Kanum
Thupten Chozing Kanum Thupten Choezing
Lamas and Scholars
Choegon Rinpoche Khadura Choegen Rinpoche
Kachen Lama
Wangchu Dorje Jangi Wangju Dorje or Wangchuk Dorje
Tibetans
Konchok Gyaltsen Khenchen Konchok Gyaltsen
Ontrul Rinpoche Ontul Rinpoche
Unknown
Tenzin Yangkyi
Ponlop Rinpoche